Guide to the Provost's Office, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Administrative files, 1919-1964; Series I
  - Reserve Officers List, 1950-1951 (Box 57, Folder 550)
  - Retrenchment, 1950-1957 (Box 57, Folder 551)
  - Rockefeller Foundation, 1935-1957 (Box 57, Folder 552 - 554)
  - Romance Languages, 1923-1929 (Box 57, Folder 555)
  - S, 1938-1956 (Box 57, Folder 556)
  - Salaries: general, 1926-1933 (Box 58, Folder 557)
  - Salaries: statistics, 1927-1931 (Box 58, Folder 558 - 559)
  - Saxon, O. Glenn, 1936-1951 (Box 58, Folder 560)
  - Scholarships, Committee on, 1944-1956 (Box 58, Folder 561 - 565)
  - Scholarships, Committee on, 1930-1944 (Box 59, Folder 566 - 567)
  - Scholarships, Sons of Faculty, 1930-1955 (Box 59, Folder 568 - 570)
  - Science, Committee on, 1930-1934 (Box 59, Folder 571)
  - Science at Yale, 1938-1939 (Box 59, Folder 572)
  - Secretary, Office of the, 1924-1957 (Box 60, Folder 573)
  - Selective Service, Committee on, 1941-1952 (Box 60, Folder 574 - 575)
  - Semitic Languages, Department of, 1920-1938 (Box 60, Folder 576)
  - Service Bureaus, 1925-1954 (Box 60, Folder 577)
  - Seymour, Charles: correspondence, 1937-1947 (Box 60, Folder 578)
  - Shakespeare Institute, 1959-1961 (Box 60, Folder 579)
  - Sheffield Scientific School, 1923-1960 (Box 60, Folder 580 - 582)
  - Sheffield Scientific School, Fund Raising, 1946 (Box 61, Folder 583)
  - Simpson Report, 1958 (Box 61, Folder 584)
  - Social Sciences, 1926-1938 (Box 61, Folder 585)
  - Social Sciences and History, Committee on, 1955-1956 (Box 61, Folder 586)
  - Social Security, 1950-1951 (Box 61, Folder 587)
  - Social Studies, Committee on, 1949-1955 (Box 61, Folder 588)
  - Social Work, 1938-1945 (Box 61, Folder 589)
  - Sociology, Department of, 1936-1958 (Box 61, Folder 590 - 591)
  - Southeast Asia and Indonesia, 1929-1956 (Box 62, Folder 592 - 594)
  - Space Committee, 1953-1956 (Box 62, Folder 595)
  - Spanish and Italian, Department of, 1949-1958 (Box 62, Folder 596)
  - Special Gifts, Committee on, 1946-1947 (Box 62, Folder 597)
  - State, Department of (United States), 1946-1961 (Box 62, Folder 598)
  - Statistics, Committee on, 1938-1961 (Box 62, Folder 599 - 602)
  - Sterling Professorships, 1928-1944 (Box 63, Folder 603 - 604)
  - Stimson, Henry L. Fund, 1951-1957 (Box 63, Folder 605 - 607)
  - Student Aid, 1952-1957 (Box 63, Folder 608 - 610)
  - Student Appointment Bureau, 1954-1955 (Box 63, Folder 611)
  - Student Appointment Bureau, 1945-1953 (Box 64, Folder 612 - 613)
  - Succession to the Presidency, Committee on, 1949 (Box 64, Folder 614)
  - Summer Session, 1945-1949 (Box 64, Folder 615)
  - Tax Bill H.R. 8920, 1950 (Box 64, Folder 616)
  - Three Term Program, 1941-1942 (Box 64, Folder 617)
  - Transportation, Committee on, 1919-1958 (Box 64, Folder 618 - 619)
    See also: Highway Traffic, Bureau of, box 32, folder 318
  - Travel Fund, 1955-1958 (Box 64, Folder 620)
  - Treasurer's Office, 1952-1957 (Box 64, Folder 621 - 622)
  - Treasurer's Office, 1930-1951 (Box 65, Folder 623 - 625)
  - Tuition Increase, 1954 (Box 65, Folder 626)
  - Undergraduate Affairs, 1924-1957 (Box 65, Folder 627)
  - Undergraduate Charges, 1940 (Box 65, Folder 628)
  - Undergraduate Reorganization Committee, 1927-1928 (Box 65, Folder 629)
  - University Church, 1927-1945 (Box 65, Folder 630)
  - University Development, Committee on, 1939-1949 (Box 65, Folder 631)
  - University Organization, Committee on, 1950-1951 (Box 66, Folder 632)
  - University, Organization of, 1928-1932 (Box 66, Folder 633)
  - University Policy, Committee on: Federal support of scientific research, 1945 (Box 66, Folder 634)
  - Vander Poel Committee, 1938-1949 (Box 66, Folder 635)
  - Veterans Affairs, Selective Service: Foreign Nationals, 1944-1960 (Box 66, Folder 636 - 637)
  - Vocational Counseling Service, 1948-1949 (Box 66, Folder 638)
  - War and Defense Studies, 1940-1943 (Box 66, Folder 639)
  - War Council, University, 1942-1943 (Box 66, Folder 640)
  - War Department, 1942-1947 (Box 66, Folder 641)
  - Whitney, John Hay Fellow, 1950-1959 (Box 66, Folder 642)
  - Whitney, John Hay Foundation, 1953-1958 (Box 66, Folder 643)
  - Work Sheets, 1943-1950 (Box 66, Folder 644)
  - Work Sheets, 1927-1941 (Box 67, Folder 645)
  - Yacht Clubs: Vineyard Haven, Southern Massachusetts Yacht Racing Association, Inc., 1960-1961 (Box 67, Folder 646)
  - Yale Broadcasting Company, 1958 (Box 67, Folder 647)
  - Yale Clubs, 1931-1935 (Box 67, Folder 648)
  - Yale College, 1923-1942 (Box 67, Folder 649 - 651)
  - Yale College Faculty, Committee on the Constitution of, 1936-1938 (Box 67, Folder 652)
  - Yale Graduate Placement Bureau, 1930 (Box 67, Folder 653)
  - Yale Studies for Returning Servicemen, 1944-1947 (Box 67, Folder 654)
  - Yale University Press, 1948-1955,1962 (Box 67, Folder 655)
  - Yale University Press, 1930-1947 (Box 68, Folder 656 - 659)
  - Zoology, Department of, 1921-1962 (Box 68, Folder 660 - 663)
- Committee minutes, 1914-1951; Series II
  - Committee on Colleges, 1933 - 1934 (Box 69, Folder 1)
  - Council of Masters
    - 1932 Mar - 1936 May (Box 70, Folder 2)
    - 1936 Oct - 1941 Jun (Box 70, Folder 3)
    - 1941 Oct - 1944 May (Box 70, Folder 4)
    - 1944 Sep - 1947 Jun (Box 70, Folder 5)
    - 1947 Sep - 1951 Jun (Box 71, Folder 6)
  - Educational Policy Committee
    - 1933 Jun - 1941 May (Box 71, Folder 7)
    - 1914 Apr - 1933 Apr (Box 72, Folder 8)
  - Prudential Committee and Yale Corporation
    - 1919 Dec (Box 72, Folder 9)
    - 1920 Jan - May (Box 72, Folder 10)
    - 1920 Jun - Dec (Box 72, Folder 11)
    - 1921 Jan - Jun (Box 73, Folder 12)
    - 1921 Jul - Dec (Box 73, Folder 13)
    - 1922 Jan - May (Box 73, Folder 14)
    - 1922 Jun - Dec (Box 73, Folder 15)
    - 1923 Jan - Mar (Box 73, Folder 16)
    - 1923 Apr - Jun (Box 73, Folder 17)
    - 1923 Jul - Dec (Box 73, Folder 18)
    - 1924 Jan - Mar (Box 73, Folder 19)
    - 1924 Apr - Jun (Box 74, Folder 20)
    - 1924 Sep - Dec (Box 74, Folder 21)
    - 1925 Jan - May (Box 74, Folder 22)
    - 1925 Jun - Dec (Box 74, Folder 23)
    - 1926 Jan - Mar (Box 74, Folder 24)
    - 1926 Apr - Jun (Box 74, Folder 25)
    - 1926 Oct - Dec (Box 74, Folder 26)
    - 1927 Jan - May (Box 74, Folder 27)
    - 1927 Jun - Dec (Box 75, Folder 28)
    - 1928 Jan (Box 75, Folder 29)
    - 1928 Feb - Jun (Box 75, Folder 30)
    - 1928 Oct - 1929 Jun (Box 75, Folder 31)
    - 1929 Oct - 1930 Jun (Box 75, Folder 32)
    - 1930 Oct - 1931 Jun (Box 76, Folder 33)
    - 1931 Oct - 1932 Jun (Box 76, Folder 34)
    - 1932 Oct - 1933 Jun (Box 76, Folder 35)
    - 1933 Oct - 1934 Jun (Box 77, Folder 36)
    - 1934 Oct - 1935 Jun (Box 77, Folder 37)
- Records of Edgar Furniss, Accession 1956-A-001; 2.25; (5 boxes) (Box 1–5)
- Records of Norman S. Buck and Kingman Brewster, Jr., 1955-1964; Accession 1964-A-002
  - Buildings and Grounds
    - Anthropology Center, 1956-1957 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Corporation, Faculty, and University Committees on Buildings and Grounds
      - Minutes of meetings
        - 1955-1959 October (Box 1, Folder 2)
        - 1960-1962 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Correspondence etc.
        - 1955-1956 (Box 1, Folder 4)
        - 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 5)
        - 1959 (Box 1, Folder 6)
        - 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 7)
        - 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Dunham Laboratory, 1956-1958 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - "Fringe lands", 1955 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Greeley Laboratory, 1956-1958 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - High School Area, Tower Parkway, 1955-1956 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Married student housing, 1957-1958 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Oak Street development, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Ornitohology and Oceanography wing, 1955-1958 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Site planning (long range planning), 1957 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Faculty of Arts and Sciences
    - Budgets
      - Brewster correspondence
        - 1962-1964 (Box 3, Folder 17)
        - 1961-1964 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Property Budgets
    - Correspondence, 1962-1964 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - 1963-1964 (Box 3, Folder 20 - 22)
  - School Budgets
    - Brewster correspondence, 1962-1964 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Corporation committee meetings, 1926-1961; Accession 1983-A-037
  - Prudential Committee and Corporation Minutes
    - 1935-1936 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1936-1937 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1938-1939 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1939-1940 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - 1940-1941 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - 1941-1942 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - 1942-1943 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - 1943-1944 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - 1944-1945 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - 1945-1946 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - 1946-1947 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - 1947-1948 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - 1948-1949 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - 1949-1950 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - 1950-1951 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - 1951-1952 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - 1952-1953 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - 1953-1954 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Corporation Minutes
    - 1954-1955 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - 1955-1956 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - 1956-1957 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - 1957-1958 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - 1958-1959 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - 1959-1960 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - College Minutes/General Faculty Permanent Officers
    - 1926 February 25 - 1946 June 13 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - 1946 October - 1954 June (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Divinity School Minutes, 1928 July - 1949 June (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Educational Planning Committee Minutes, 1938 November - 1946 December (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Educational Policy Committee Minutes
    - 1941 October 10 - 1950 June (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - 1950 November -1959 May (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Executive Committee of the Faculty of Arts and Sciences Minutes, 1956 September -1961 March (Box 8, Folder 32)
- Records of Kingman Brewster as provost, 1960-1963; Accession 2002-A-079
  - Police Dept. Annual Report, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence
    - Miscellaneous, 1960-1962 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1960 Apr 12 - 1962 Apr 14 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1962 Apr 17 - May 21 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1962 May 25 - Nov (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1962 Dec - 1963 Mar 1 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Proclamation from Yale University Press to Edgar Furniss, 1957; Accession 2016-A-055
  - Proclamation presented to Edgar Furniss by Yale University Press upon his retirement, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 1)